NOELIA ALCALÁ GARCÍA

Phone: +44 7858 922235

Email: nalcalag@gmail.com

Website: https://nalcalag.github.io/
GitHub: https://github.com/nalcalag

167/4 Easter Road EH7 5QB Edinburgh

I am a cheerful and positive person who enjoys developing native Android Apps. I love technologies and learn as much as possible everyday, whether studying a Master's, doing a course in coursera.org or in Lynda.com. I am open to find a native Android developer job where I can learn and grow personally and professionally. I am responsible, good at problem solving and work hard to achieve all my goals. I would like to use my experience and my adaptability to learn as much as possible.

SKILLS

Software Development (Mobile and Web): Kotlin, Java, XML, HTML, CSS, Android SDK, Ionic, JSON, Realm, SQLite, Room persistence, Swift, Wordpress.

Android libraries: Retrofit, Dagger2, RxJava, Butterknife, Picasso, Firebase, Pusher, Crashlytics, Google Services.

Version Control: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, GitLab

Testing: JUnit, Espresso.

Develop Tools: Android Studio, Dreamweaver, Visual Studio, Xcode.

Design Tools: balsamiq, Photoshop, Adobe Ilustrator.

Project Management Tools: JIRA, Microsoft Project Professional, zoho.

Text Editors: Sublime, Notepad++, WebStorm, Visual Studio Code.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MTC Media, Scotland

August 2017 – Present

Android Developer

- · Design and build native applications for the Android platform using kotlin, RxJava, Dagger, Butterknife, Retrofit, etc.
- · Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- · Work with outside data sources and APIs.
- · Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- · Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

APS Group, Scotland

January 2016 - May 2017

Digital Media Engineer

APS Group is a marketing solutions & customer communications company. They support important companies throughout the whole marketing process from strategy to delivery. My duties involved:

- **Web conversions**: Follow a process to transform PDF documents to HTML/CSS code for Scottish Government Publications
- Web Development: Build themes from designs for Wordpress (PHP, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript)
- Android APPs development: We built an Android app for Church of Scotland Events. (Android Studio, Java, XML, Android SDK, Realm DataBase, JSON, Publishing apps)
- **Testing:** Formal process to verify and validate that deliverables fulfills all the requirements before publishing.

ONO (Vodafone Company), Spain

June 2012 to April 2015

Online Technician

The website of a company like Ono covers lots of content. During this time, I had the opportunity to specialize in the client area, help and support, and online store. My duties involved:

- Maintenance and management of improvements of the Online store: Manage every month
 marketing release deciding which new features had to be available on the webpage, keeping release
 notes up-to-date and team informed.
- **Troubleshooting:** Solve customer incidences on the website. Bug reporting and bug tracking using a CRM (Clarify).
- **Usability and testing:** We considered usability principles to make improvements or new projects on the website (Accessibility, Clarity, Consistency) and then we tested everything was how we required.
- **Project management:** Planning and defining scope (new or current customers, SMEs or particulars), time estimating, write requirements' specification and monitoring and reporting progress (JIRA and internal tools).
- Development of complaints and claims flows for customers self assessment (Software Development)
- Analysis Reporting: Collecting data from an internal tool about the sales on the online store, analyse all of the data, deliver ad hoc reports and present them to my supervisor and manager.

Varadero Software Factory, Spain Internships as Web Developer

February 2011 to August 2011

- HTML + CSS layout
- Testing and quality control

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Master in Mobile Application Development

2016 - Present

Universitat Oberta de Cataluya (Barcelona, Spain) Online

I would like to join the world's fastest growing IT employment sector by studying this Master with a full and in-depth training. It covers a wide range of programming languages and platforms:

- Fundamentals of mobile technology and App development specifications
- Development of native Android Apps (Android Studio)
- Development of native iOS Apps (Xcode)
- Development of hybrids apps: HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript and Ionic framework.

Master in Professional Development 3.0

2013 - 2014

University of Alcalá (Madrid, Spain)

This course gave me the opportunity to professionally improve thanks to the wide variety of business content studied.

Telecommunications Engineering

2008 - 2014

The Polytechnic University of Madrid (Madrid, Spain)

Final degree based on the development of a self-management online tool for troubleshooting of TV decoder.

Elektrotechnik (Erasmus Scholarship)

2011 - 2012

Ostfalia Hochschule für angewandte Wissenschaften (Wolfenbüttel, Germany)

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native Language

English: Upper-Intermediate Listener, Upper-Intermediate Speaker, Advanced Reading and Writing

German: Elementary Listener, Elementary Speaker, Elementary Reading and Writing